<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on My idees and reflections</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on My idees and reflections</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Agree or disagree?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/agree_or_disagree/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/agree_or_disagree/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;two-ways-to-agree&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Two ways to agree&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#two-ways-to-agree&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you talk with someone and you want to express agreement you can say:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is not false&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;it is true&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But it seems saying one or another does not amount to the same thing. If you say, agreeing to someone saying for instance &amp;lsquo;it is good to think before acting&amp;rsquo;. Now if you concede to this point, saying &amp;lsquo;it is true&amp;rsquo;, you agree with the point without distinguishing any nuance. For example, if you walk in nature and you see a charging bull, it might be a good idea to quickly jump on a nearby tree and think &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; the fact, not before. You basically run on survival instincts and there is no time to think, it&amp;rsquo;s too slow and would cost you your life. This works well in primitive environment where dangers are acute and well visible. So saying it is good to think before acting is not always true, since the difference between life and death is seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Map is not reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/map_is_not_reality/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/map_is_not_reality/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-use-map-to-navigate-world&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Don&amp;rsquo;t use map to navigate world&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#dont-use-map-to-navigate-world&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maps can be dangerous, by giving us false comfort and by fooling us that they are the reality where in fact they are always some reduction and deformation to some degree, since one big object cannot be compressed  10000 times and we expect then that’s identical than the big object.&#xA;Or put a toy car next to real car, or architectural maquette of a building next to real one. You cannot live in the maquette building, you can’t go shopping in toy car, you know the difference, but why everyone , including me, mixes up models ( opinion of a thing vs real qualities that can be objectively measured). Why do we believe in dogmas then ( all sorts of, like economy , psychology, théorie de xyZ….) can be due to the fact it’s complex vs simple ( toy car vs theory of time travel) one easy to imagine the other not - but in primitive environment we didn’t worry about time travel speed. We wanted to survive. Now take this caveman into the Time Machine and tell him to go to work in Wall Street - he would go crazy - but both the caveman and the bankers have the same genes, except that the caveman maybe a lot more smarter then some of them, but that’s for another topic on if humanity gets smarter or not. But caveman would mistrust the maps and models , he would use reality heuristics. We are baffled by the noise like that caveman and make all sorts of mistakes on this complex system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On servility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/on_servility/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/on_servility/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;servility-is-a-form-of-flattery&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Servility is a form of flattery&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#servility-is-a-form-of-flattery&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All flattery is fatal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The exaggerated or maybe any for that matter, servility ( shoe licking, subordinance) are the forms of flattery. This is &lt;strong&gt;flattery in disguise&lt;/strong&gt;, because if someone comports towards you as a subordinate, it boosts your ego. You might think that this is rather a form of deception ( this fundamentally, morally attitude of servility). When someone is deceived, he does not know that he is deceived at the moment of being deceived. One can only talk about deception in view post factum. One might ( a group, nation ) been deceived without being aware of the process of being deceived ( as this is the very nature of deception itself ). A whole century can pass or more, so that no one living in the deception will ever be aware, since they will pass away before the 100 years revelation date ( unexpected, black swan type event, this revelation is ). Think of blood lettings, lobotomy, belinging that earth is flat, etc.  But when one is being flatted by someone’s servility , we know that it’s fake and suspicious, or at least we should, and and being aware of  the deception and allowing it to happen nevertheless is weakness of mind. The one who deceives would always be guided by his personal interests unless he is imbecile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Varous thoughts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;varous-topics&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Varous topics&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#varous-topics&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thoughts flow on various subjects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Dogs and animals domesticated is a wolf breeded too closely and it came out some sort of retard. That’s how it started since human got wolves mates in captivity ( for sacrifice maybe ? - Rene Girard). The same with cows. How about humans, are they also domesticated?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Anti fragilité  - ce qui n enrichie pas - fais un plus pauvre - au temps l’argent l’amitié  etc.. tous… grâce à covex - concave. Covex c’est l’opposite de concave Soit tu es malin ou dupe il n’y a pas un mielieu. Hence gros Tony categorized people only by dupes and non dupes. There’s nothing in the middle&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:kamil.szewczyk.p@gmail.com&#34;&gt;kamil.szewczyk.p@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
